It's you, Kiritsugu.
切嗣だ
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界の為に
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
紅く汚された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
I'm not dreaming, am I?
夢じゃないのね
You really...
ホントに また 会いに来てくれたのね
...came to see me again.
ああ そうだよ
Yes, that's right.
ありがとう
Thank you.
最後に
Lastly, I need to return this to you.
これを返さないとね
これは 「全て遠き理想郷」は
You're the one who'll need Avalon from now on.
この先あなたにこそ必要な物
あなたが最後の戦いに挑む時
When you fight your final battle, I'm sure it'll aid you.
きっと役に立つ
私はね 幸せだよ
You know...
I really am happy.
I've loved... and I've been loved.
恋をして 愛されて
I've had a husband and a daughter for nine whole years.
夫と娘と 九年も
あなたは 全てを与えてくれた
You gave me everything.
私には望むべくもなかった
All the happiness in the world that was never meant for me.
この世の幸せの全てを
すまない 君にはもっと外の世界を見せたかった
I'm sorry.
I wanted to show you more of the outside world.
No.
ううん もういいの
It's fine.
私が取りこぼした幸せがあるなら
If there's any happiness that I have yet to experience, give it all to Ilya.
残りは全部 イリヤにあげて
あなたの娘に
Your daughter...
私達の 大切なイリヤに
Our beloved Ilya.
いつかイリヤをこの国に連れてきてあげて
Don't forget to bring Ilya to this country one day.
あの子に 私が見られなかった物を全部見せてあげて
Show her everything I wasn't able to see.
桜の花を
The cherry blossoms...
夏の雲を
The summer clouds...
分かった
I will.
じゃあ 行ってくるよ
Well, I'll be going now.
はい お気をつけて
Okay, take care.
あなた
My love...
セイバーはライダーの潜伏先に向かっているな
Saber is heading to Rider's hideout, right?
Yes. She's on her way.
はい すでに
I'll go and kill Tohsaka Tokiomi.
僕は遠阪時臣を仕留める
When Saber and Rider fight, there's a
good chance Archer will appear there.
セイバーがライダーとことを起こせば
アーチャーもその場に現れる公算が大きい
I'll use that opportunity.
そこをつく
You continue to watch over Iri.
君は引き続きアイリの警護を頼む
Understood.
分かりました
Um... Kiritsugu.
あの 切嗣
やっと 戻りましたね
You... finally look like your old self.
昔のあなたの顔に
サーヴァントの気配は感じない
I don't sense a Servant's presence.
Packs:   Body Warmer
結界が張られてない どういうことだ
There's no magic field.
What could this mean?
美味いのか そりゃあ
Does that taste good?
Nope. It's awful.
いいや 不味い
Japanese food has really reached new lows.
日本の食文化も底が知れるな
Boy, you walked right past Okonomiyaki Shouki in the new town.
坊主 貴様さっき新都で『お好み焼き鍾馗』を素通りしおったな？
あそこのモダン焼きは絶品であったというのに
Their modanyaki was absolutely superb.
惜しいことを
Pity you didn't buy any.
If you want to eat there again, hurry up and recover enough to assume corporeal form.
また食いたいんなら
さっさと実体化できるぐらいまで回復しろよ
You know what this place is, right?
ここが何処か分かってるよな
It's where I summoned you.
お前を召喚した場所だよ
The Fuyuki ley lines most compatible with you run through here, right?
お前にとって
冬木で一番相性のいい地脈はここだろ
You should be able to recover much faster.
回復の効率も段違いに捗るはずだ
I'll be staying here all day.
僕は今日一日ここにいる
I won't do anything except sleep,
何もしないで寝てるから
so take as much mana as you want, as long as it doesn't kill me.
死なない程度で
いくらでも魔力を持って行けばいい
It should help you recover.
そうすれば お前も少しはマシになるだろ
So you already know? You should've told me when you found out.
気付いたなら気付いた時にそう言えよ
Finding out later that someone's seen right through you is, well...
後になって見透されていたと分かるってのは なんだ
It's a little embarrassing.
うん いささか面映ゆいぞ
You idiot!
バカ お前こそさっさと言えよ
You're the one who should've spoken up.
I'm the one who'll be in danger if you aren't at your best when I need you!
いざって時にお前が満足に動けないようじゃ
危ないのは僕の方なんだからな
Why didn't you say anything?
なんで黙ってたんだよ ずっと
I thought I could hold out a little longer,
もう少し踏ん張りがきくかと思っておったのだがな
but the energy expenditure from the
river battle was greater than I expected.
河での戦闘の消耗が 思いのほか堪えてなあ
So in the end, your trump card uses up a ton of mana.
結局 お前の切り札って実はとんでもなく魔力を食い潰すんだろ
最初は見過ごしてたよ
I just ignored it at first.
You didn't pass on any of the costs to me, so I thought your Noble Phantasm was ridiculously efficient.
僕には全然皺寄せが来ないから
並外れて効率のいい宝具なのかと思ってた
Rider.
ライダー
本当はお前 僕が負担するべき分の魔力まで
You used the mana from your own stores
in place of mana I should've supplied, right?
自前の貯蔵魔力だけで賄ってきたんだろ
You even did it twice, reckless as it was.
その上で二度もあんな無茶やらかして
一体全体 どういう了見だ？
What the heck was that all about?
Well, you see...
だって なあ
まぁ 正味の処
When you get right down to it, I'm a Servant and therefore a natural soul eater.
サーヴァントとしての余は生粋の魂喰らいであるからにして
全開の魔力消費に坊主を巻き込めば
If I made you bear the cost while expending
my mana at full force, it could endanger your life.
その時は命すら危うくしかねんからな
僕は それでいいんだ
I'm fine with that.
これは僕が始めた戦いだ
This is a battle I chose to fight.
僕が血を流して 犠牲を払って
If I don't shed blood or make sacrifices,
その上で勝ち上がんなきゃ 意味がないんだ
there's no point if I end up winning.
僕はな ただ証明したいだけだ
I just want to prove it.
That I...
この僕が こんな僕にだって
That I, too, can win such things!
この手で掴み取れるものがあるんだってことを
だが坊主 そいつは聖杯が本当にあった場合の話だよな
But that only applies if the Grail actually exists, boy.
余はな 以前にもそういう「在るか無いかも知れぬモノ」を
You know, I once fought for something that might not have even existed. Just like you.
追いかけて戦ったことがある
最果ての海
Ôkeanos.
That's right.
そうだ
「最果ての海」を見せてやると
I told everyone I'd show them Ôkeanos,
そういう口上を吹き散らし
and they all believed me and followed without a doubt.
余の口車に乗って疑いもせずついてきたお調子者を随分と死なせた
Many died.
皆最後まで余の語った「最果ての海」を夢見ておった
They were all dreaming of this
Ôkeanos I spoke of, right until the end.
When I gained the knowledge of this era, it really hit me.
この時代の知識を得た時は まあ結構 堪えたわい
まさか大地が丸く閉じているなんて
I had no idea the Earth was round and closed.
What a bad joke.
悪い冗談にもほどがある
だがそれでも地図を見れば納得するしかなかった
But even so, when I saw the map,
I had no choice but to accept it.
余はなあ
I've had enough of people dying for fairy tales.
もう その手の与太話で誰かを死なせるのは嫌なんだ
Were the Grail's location certain, I'd have no objection to you risking your life.
聖杯の在処が確かなら
命を賭けようという貴様の意気込みに報いてやることもできようが
生憎 まだそうとも言いきれぬ
But unfortunately, it isn't.
Even so...
それでも
Even so, I...
それでも僕は お前のマスターなんだぞ
I'm your Master!
坊主 貴様も言うようになったではないか
Boy...
You've really learned to talk back, haven't you?
確かに魔術回路の方も 普段より威勢良く廻っとる
It's also true that your Magic Circuits are flowing far better than usual.
日中を休息に費やせば
If we rest during the day, we'll be ready for more action come nightfall!
夜にはまた一暴れできそうだ
And?
What exactly do you mean by more action?
一暴れって 次は何やらかすつもりだ お前
Let's see.
そうさなあ
Why don't we start with Saber this evening?
今夜は じゃあ
まずセイバーの奴でも相手にしてやるか
At this rate, how much will you recover by tonight?
この調子で夜までにどの程度回復できそうだ お前
「神威の車輪」の使用は飛ばすだけなら問題なかろう
If I use the Gordius Wheel only for flight, there shouldn't be a problem.
However...
だが「王の軍勢」はおそらくあと一回の展開が限度だな
I think I'll only be able to use Ionian Hetairoi one last time.
そうか
I see...
We should probably save it for the fight with Archer.
使いどころとしては 対アーチャー戦だな
In that case, Rider...
だったら ライダー
Why do you want to fight Saber?
なんでわざわざセイバーとも戦うんだ
セイバーの奴めはな 余が倒さねばならんのだ
Saber is someone I have to defeat.
それが英霊としての余の務めだ
It's my duty as a Heroic Spirit.
What the heck's that?
何だ それ
あの馬鹿娘は
If I don't show that stupid girl the right path, she'll never learn.
余が正しく征してやらねば
永遠に道を踏み誤ったままだろうて
それではあまりに不憫過ぎる
That would be too sad.
まあ 好きにすればいいさ
Well, do what you want.
いいから 無理せんで寝てろ坊主
Just go ahead and sleep, boy.
今の貴様には休息こそが戦いだ
Rest is the battle you face right now.
我は疎まれし者
I am the repugnant.
嘲られし者
The scorned.
蔑まれし者
The despised.
お前は誰だ
Who are you?
我が名は賛歌に値せず
My name is unworthy of praise.
我が身は羨望に値ぜず
My body unworthy of envy.
我は英霊の輝きが産んだ影
I am the shadow cast by the light of a Heroic Spirit.
眩き伝説の陰に生じた闇
The darkness born from the shadow of a shining legend.
Thus, do I hate.
故に我は憎悪する
我は怨嗟する
Thus, do I resent.
闇に沈みし者の嘆きを糧にして
I feed on the cries of those who sink into darkness
光り輝くあの者たちを呪う
and curse those who shine brilliantly.
Her image is my shame.
あの貴影こそ我が恥辱
その誉れが不朽であるが故
Her honor remains untarnished, and
thus I am forever looked down upon.
我もまた永久に貶められる
貴様は
You are...
...the sacrifice!
贄だ
治療しても無駄だ
Healing won't help me.
I'm going to die soon.
もうじき 俺は死ぬ
畜生
Damn it...
まったく随分なザマになり果てたのう 雁夜よ
Really, look at how pathetic you are now, Kariya.
Don't get the wrong idea.
勘違いするでないぞ
I'm not blaming you.
ワシはなにも責めておるのではない
正直なところ
To be honest, I never even imagined that you'd last this long.
まさか貴様がここまで食い下がるとは予想しておらんなんだ
And so, I shall give you the ultimate
trump card I've stowed away for this stage.
そこで
貴様にはワシがここ一番の局面に備えて秘蔵しておった切り札を授けてやる
Now...
さあ
覿面じゃのう
That was fast.
今貴様に呑ませた淫蟲はな
The worm I just gave you was the first to feed on Sakura's purity.
桜の純潔を最初に啜った一匹よ
どうだ 雁夜よ
How does it feel, Kariya?
この一年じっくりと喰らいに喰らった娘の精気
For an entire year, it's been devouring the girl's life energy.
極上の魔力であろう
It's a magnificent mana source.
Now, go and fight, Kariya.
さあ 戦うがいい雁夜
Make good use of the life you've stolen from Sakura.
桜から奪ったその命 存分に燃やし尽くせ
血肉も骨も残さず費やして聖杯を掴むがいい
Use every ounce of your flesh and bone to acquire the Grail.
If you even can, that is.
貴様ごときに出来るものならな
ねえ 舞弥さん
Hey, Maiya-san.
Why do you fight for Kiritsugu?
あなたはなぜ切嗣のために戦うの
それ以外に何もないからです
Because I have nothing else.
私には家族のことも自分の名前も思い出せない
I don't remember my family or my name.
久宇舞弥という名前は
Hisau Maiya was the name on the first fake passport Kiritsugu made for me.
切嗣が最初に作ってくれた偽造パスポートの名義です
All I remember about my home country is its extreme poverty.
覚えているのは
そこがどうしようもなく貧しい国だったということだけ
The wars never ended, even though there was no money to maintain the armies.
戦争は決して終わらず 軍隊を維持する資金さえないのに
それでも殺し合いを続けるしかない毎日
But each day, they continued to kill one another.
そのうちに 誰かが思いついたんです
And then, someone had an idea.
兵隊を徴用して訓練するより
Rather than conscript and train soldiers,
子供を攫ってきて銃を持たせた方が安上がりで手っ取り早いとね
they decided it'd be cheaper and quicker to kidnap kids and arm them.
Maiya-san, you...
舞弥さん あなた
Aim at the enemy and pull the trigger.
敵を狙って引き金を引く
私はそういう機能だけを残して
That was my sole function.
I threw everything else away.
後は全てを捨て去りました
私は人として中身が死んでいる
As a human being, I'm dead inside.
ただ外側の器だけがまだ動いて
But my body continues to move,
still working like it did before.
昔馴染みの機能を維持しています
それが私の生命です
That is my life.
But Kiritsugu took me in anyway.
そんな私を拾ったのは切嗣だ
だから切嗣が好きなように使ってくれればいい
So he can use me however he wants.
それが私がここにいる理由です
That's the reason I'm here.
むしろ私には マダム
In fact, Madam, it's your passion that's surprising.
貴女の熱意こそ意外だった
貴女は生まれ育った城に閉じ込められたまま
You've been shut inside the castle where you were born, living without experiencing the outside world.
外の世界を知らずに生きてきた
So I can't imagine why you'd fight this hard to help Kiritsugu change the world.
そんな貴女が世界を変革しようという切嗣のために
あれほど必死になって戦うだなんて
I...
私は
そうね
You're right.
There's no way I could truly understand Kiritsugu's ideals.
本当は切嗣の理想がどういうものか
きちんと理解できているわけではないわ
舞弥さんの言う通り
It's as you say.
私は切嗣が変えようとしている世界のことをまるで分かってない
I don't understand a thing about
the world Kiritsugu is trying to change.
私の理想なんて 何もかも切嗣の受け売りでしかないわ
I simply borrowed all of my ideals from him.
でも切嗣には内緒
But don't let him know that.
I've always told him that he's doing the right thing.
切嗣にはいつだって 彼が正しいと言い聞かせてきた
I've told him those ideals are worth my life.
彼の理想には私が命を捧げるだけの価値があるってね
そうやって理解者のふりをしてきたわ
And I pretended to understand him.
Then, Madam, do you have no wish of your own?
ではマダム 貴女には貴女自身のための願いはないと
願いは
A wish?
いいえ 確かにある
No, I have one.
I wish for Kiritsugu and Saber to win the Holy Grail.
私は切嗣とセイバー あの二人に聖杯を掴み取って欲しい
Is that the Einzbern desire, the attainment of the third true magic?
それは第三魔法の達成という アインツベルンの悲願ですか
No.
いいえ 私が求めているのは戦いの終焉よ
What I desire is an end to the conflict.
If Kiritsugu's wish comes true and
all the fighting everywhere ceases,
切嗣の願いが叶って 全ての闘争が終焉するならば
the fight for the Grail here in Fuyuki City should be no exception.
ここ冬木で聖杯を求め争う戦いについても例外じゃないはずでしょう
どうか今回の四度目を最後の聖杯戦争にしてほしいの
I want this fourth battle to be the last Holy Grail War there will be.
ご息女のことですか
For your daughter?
もし私と切嗣が失敗すれば
If Kiritsugu and I fail, it will be Ilya's turn next.
次はイリヤが
It is the destiny of every Einzbern homunculus.
でもそれがアインツベルンのホムンクルスに背負わされた宿命なのよ
That's why I want to be the last one.
だから私は私で最後にしたい
もしそれが叶えば
If that comes to pass, Ilya'll be able
to live out her life as a human being.
あの子は最後まで人として生きていくことができる
舞弥さん
Maiya-san.
あなたは切嗣が理想を遂げた後 どうするつもり
What will you do after Kiritsugu reaches his goal?
生き残るなどと考えてはいません
I don't expect to survive.
もし仮に命を繋いだとしても
Even if I do, there'd be no reason for me to exist.
もう私に生きる意味はない
I'm sure that's what the world will be like once Kiritsugu has changed it.
切嗣によって変革された世界というのはきっとそういう場所でしょう
No, that's not true.
ううん そんなことはない
そうでしょうか
You think so?
You have to look for your real name and family!
捜さないと あなたの本当の名前と家族を
Those aren't things you should forget.
それは忘れられていいことじゃない
はっきりと確かめて 刻みつけていかなきゃならないことよ
You have to find out and remember them forever.
So live, Maiya-san.
だから生きて 舞弥さん
For me, too.
私の分も
善処はします
I'll do my best.
でもそれは 戦いが終わった後の話です
But that will be after the battle has ended.
Right now, we must be cautious.
現状では予断を許さない
He and I must stay on guard.
彼も 私も 当面は気を抜くことなどできません
死んだのは遠坂時臣
It was Tohsaka Tokiomi who died.
You really are...
本当に あなたって人は
舞弥さん
Maiya-san!
Iri!
アイリ
令呪を以て我が傀儡に命ず
By my Command Spell, I order my puppet...
Saber!
セイバー 土蔵に戻れ 今すぐに
Go back to the storehouse! Now!
Kiritsugu...
切嗣
This is...
ここは
舞弥
Maiya!
Saber...
セイ バー
Don't speak.
喋ってはいけない
Hurry...
早く外へ 追ってください
Go outside and chase him...
ライダーが マダムを
Rider took Madam...
だが それでは
But then...
私は大丈夫
I'm... fine.
And soon, Kiritsugu will...
すぐに切嗣が
So... hurry.
だから 早く
舞弥 どうか切嗣が来るまで持ち堪えてください
Maiya.
Please hold out until Kiritsugu returns.
アイリスフィールは必ずや私が
I will bring Irisviel back.
Did Rider really...?!
まさか 本当にライダーが
Rider...
ライダーが
Yes, I see.
ああ 分かった
ダメだよ 泣いたら
You shouldn't cry.
それは奥さんのために とっておいて
Save those tears for your wife...
ここで泣いたら ダメ
You can't cry here.
あなた 弱いから
You're weak.
That's why you shouldn't... break down just yet...
今はまだ 壊れちゃ ダメ
I...
僕は
This morning, you finally looked like your old self.
今朝やっと 昔のままの切嗣になったんだから
You can't waver now...
こんなことで揺れたら ダメ
Don't worry, Maiya.
安心しろ 舞弥
後はセイバーに任せろ
Leave the rest to Saber.
舞弥 お前の役目は
Maiya, you have fulfilled...
...your purpose.
終わりだ
舞弥
Maiya.
Maiya...
Episode 20
Return of the Assassin
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
Where is Irisviel?
アイリスフィールはどこだ
忘れるなよ 今夜0時だ
Don't forget. Tonight, at midnight.
Nothing can stop me!
我が疾走を阻む者はない
Don't underestimate me, King of Conquerors!
侮るなよ 征服王
It's his fault!
そいつのせいで その男さえいなければ
If it weren't for him...
Oh, scary, scary.
怖い 怖い
Are you satisfied, Kariya-kun?
Next Episode
Knight on Two Wheels
満足してる 雁夜君